<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tools | Martin]]></title>
  <link href="http://Martin91.github.io/blog/categories/tools/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Martin91.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-26T22:40:52+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://Martin91.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Martin]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DIY an interesting timer through terminal-notifier and crontab under Mac OS X]]></title>
    <link href="http://Martin91.github.io/blog/articles/2014/01/12/diy-an-interesting-timer-through-terminal-notifier-and-crontab-under-mac-os-x/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-12T15:51:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Martin91.github.io/blog/articles/2014/01/12/diy-an-interesting-timer-through-terminal-notifier-and-crontab-under-mac-os-x</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I will show you how to DIY an intersting notifier automatically running per hour under the Mac OS X 10.8 and higher, all we need are a terminal-notifier and the system built-in command line program named <code>crontab</code>.</p>

<!-- More -->


<h2>1. Install the terminal-notifier</h2>

<p><code>terminal-notifier</code> is a program written in the awesome <a href="https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/">Ruby</a> program language, we can visit <a href="https://github.com/alloy/terminal-notifier/releases">the releases page</a> and download the newest version of terminal-notifier. Steps to install it:<br/>
1. Please click the green button such as &ldquo;<strong>terminal-notifier-1.5.0.zip</strong>&rdquo; and select a path wherever you love to save the zip file;<br/>
2. After downloading completed, open the folder you selected in the above step, look for the zip file, and then double-click to extract the program;<br/>
3. Copy the extracted program <strong>terminal-notifier</strong>;<br/>
4. Click the &ldquo;Applications&rdquo; tab in the sidebar of your finder, and then paste the copied file.<br/>
5. Lastly, open a terminal and then run the following command to test if the notifier has been installed successfully.
<code>sh
/Applications/terminal-notifier.app/Contents/MacOS/terminal-notifier -title "Test Installation" -message 'your notifier has been installed successfully!'
</code>
  You will see a notification message appears. If not, re-check your installation and make sure you have finished the above steps strictly.</p>

<h2>2. Create the timer to notice you to have a break</h2>

<p>In order to run the notifier periodically, we use <code>crontab</code>, which maintains crontab files for individual users.</p>

<p>Now, please open your terminal again, and then type the following command, run it:
<code>sh
crontab -e
</code>
Append the following line to the openning file:
<code>sh
0 * * * * /Applications/terminal-notifier.app/Contents/MacOS/terminal-notifier -title "Guy, take a break please!" -message 'You have worked for a hour again, I suggest that you should take a break.'
</code>
Save the file and exit, your cron tasks will be updated automatically.</p>

<p>After every thing is finished, you will reveive the attentive message per hour. Cheers!</p>

<p>This post only acts like a demo, you can do more powerful works as you imagine.</p>

<p><strong>Related Resources:</strong><br>
  1. <a href="https://github.com/alloy/terminal-notifier">terminal-notifier</a><br>
  2. <a href="http://www.pantz.org/software/cron/croninfo.html">crontab</a><br>
  3. <a href="http://unixhelp.ed.ac.uk/CGI/man-cgi?crontab">crontab man page</a><br>
  4. <a href="http://www.thegeekstuff.com/2009/06/15-practical-crontab-examples">Linux Crontab: 15 Awesome Cron Job Examples</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
